Guide to the Alton Abraham Collection of Sun Ra 1822-2008
University of Chicago Library
- Series VII: Alton Abraham
  - Subseries 2: Science and Technology
    - Nutritional values of foods, photocopied list, undated (Box 49, Folder 21)
    - Garth W. Boericke, "Homeopathy," pamphlet, undated (Box 49, Folder 22)
  - Subseries 3: Politics and Society
    - Mary O'Hanlon, Racial Myths, pamphlet, 1946 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Charles H. Davis, Jr., "Black Nationalism and the Nation of Islam," pamphlets, 1962 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - United States Department of Commerce, "East Africa: A Market for U.S. Products" and "Market for U.S. Products in the Ivory Coast," supplements to International Commerce, 1966 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - The Real Great Society, conference proceedings and clippings, 1967 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Black Poets Reading, brochure, 1970 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Institute of Positive Education, Black Books Bulletin, 1973 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - South West Africa People's Organization of Namibia (SWAPO), Namibia News, periodicals, 1973 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Southern Africa, periodical, 1974 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Plain Truth: A Magazine of Understanding, 1975 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Herbert J. Hansell, memorandum for the secretary of state on the president's power to give notice of termination of US-ROC mutual defense treaty, photocopy, 1978 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Overthrow, periodicals, 1983-1986 (Box 50, Folder 11-13)
    - Griot: A Journal of Native Consciousness, 1992 (Box 50, Folder 14)
    - Birmingham Civil Rights Institute, brochure, undated (Box 50, Folder 15)
    - Richard Clagett, "Public Sale of Negroes," reproduction broadside, undated (Box 50, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 4: Music Instruction
    - Sheet music, 1923-1962 (Box 50, Folder 17)
    - Music workbook, 1946 (Box 50, Folder 18)
    - Mickey Baker's Complete Course in Jazz Guitar, book 1, 1955 (Box 50, Folder 19)
    - Anthony J. Manfredi and Joseph M. Estella, Smith's Modern Electric Bass Guitar Method, instruction book,1959 (Box 50, Folder 20)
    - Mel Bay, Tenor Banjo Chords in Photo-Diagram Form, instruction book, 1961 (Box 50, Folder 21)
    - Charles F. Morrison, Jr., Generalized Instrumentation for Research and Teaching, primer, 1964 (Box 50, Folder 22)
    - Authentic Guitar Sounds of Peter Paul and Mary, songbook, 1967 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - John Higgins, "Night Coach," score, 1968 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Tommy J. Fry, "Triptych," score, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - B.B. King Songbook: Black and Blue, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Kenneth Stanton, Introduction to Jazz Theory, 1976 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - The Buddy Holly Story, songbook, 1978 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Maurice J. Summerfield, The Jazz Guitar, monograph, 1978 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Country Superstars, songbook, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - The Jack Butler Piano Course, part 2, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Beatles, songbook, 1982 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 5: Knights of Music
    - "The Gately Song," score, circa 1950 (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - Sepians "Queen of May" frolic, invitation, 1950 (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - Financial records, notes and business card, circa 1950s (Box 51, Folder 13)
    - Mildred B. Haessler Ballet Group, program, 1948 (Box 51, Folder 14)
    - Concert programs, 1951-1952 (Box 51, Folder 15)
    - Certificate of membership, 1953 (Box 51, Folder 16)
    - Choral music songbooks, 1887-1952 (Box 51, Folder 17-18)
    - Choral music songbooks, 1887-1952 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 6: Entrepreneurship
    - Nationwide Plastics Company, plastic manufacturing manuals, 1962 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Bureau of Land Management, correspondence, 1966-1970 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Bureau of Land Management, Our Public Lands, periodicals, 1967- 1968 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Amway pamphlets and order form, circa 1970 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Sri Lanka State Trading Corporation, correspondence and catalog, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - J.D. Borthwick, "Notes from Three (3) Years in California," typescript, undated (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Business opportunities, correspondence, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 52, Folder 8-13)
    - Business opportunities, correspondence, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 53, Folder 1-8)
  - Subseries 7: Correspondence, Notes and Ephemera
    - Limited Editions Club, 1929-1941 catalogue, 1940 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Diplomas, certifications and registrations, 1947-circa 1980s (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - A.O. Knoll, correspondence, 1952-1958 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Madalynn Friedman, notes, 1959 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Fiat 1800 manual, 1950s (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, circa 1950s-1990s (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Chicago Transit Authority, accident report, 1960 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Adam Everett Abraham, vocabulary list, 1965 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - United States Civil Service Commission, employment application and pamphlet, 1966-1967 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Automobiles, financial records, publicity material, forms and notes, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 54, Folder 10-11)
    - Notebooks, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 54, Folder 12-13)
    - Travel ephemera and correspondence, circa 1960s-1990s (Box 55, Folder 1-2)
    - Chicago Public Library, bulletin, 1969 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Clippings, circa 1960s-1990s (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Ohio St. Matthew University, correspondence, 1970 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, automobile auction catalog, 1970 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - CPA review course schedule, 1976 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Notebook, 1978 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Horoscope, notes, 1987 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Citroën CX brochure, 1987 (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - Chicago A.R.E. study groups, list, undated (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - Business cards, undated (Box 55, Folder 12)
    - Notes, undated (Box 55, Folder 13-23)
- Series VIII: Audio-Visual
  This series contains photographs, audio recordings, and film and video recordings. Materials are organized by format into three subseries:
  Subseries 1: Photographs, contains prints, contact sheets, transparencies and negatives. There are also photocopies and printed scans of photographs. Most photographs are in black and white, though some are in color. Many photographs are undated, but generally span the 1940s-1990s. Photographs of Sun Ra and the Arkestra include portraits, photographs of live performances, candid snapshots, and publicity stills for Space is the Place. Also included are photographs of Alton Abraham, photographs of travel in Egypt in elsewhere, and photographs of other performers. There are many unidentified photographs, particularly negatives.
  Subseries 2: Film and Video, contains filmstrips and videocassette tapes. Most items are unidentified and undated, but generally date from the 1970s-1990s. Also included is an empty canister and box shipped in 1961.
  Subseries 3: Audio, contains cassette tapes, reel tapes, and vinyl records. Included are recordings by Sun Ra and other performers, as well as test pressings and unidentified recordings. Inserts, correspondence and other accompanying material is found with some recordings. Materials span 1964-1999.
  Text and graphic documents of Sun Ra performances and recordings are in Series II and III.
  - Subseries 1: Photographs
    - Sun Ra and Arkestra, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Sun Ra and Arkestra, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Sun Ra and Arkestra, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Sun Ra and Arkestra, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Sun Ra and Arkestra, circa 1950s, 2002 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Sun Ra and other performers, circa 1960s (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Sun Ra and other performers, circa 1960s (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Sun Ra and other performers, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Sun Ra and other performers, Space is the Place, circa 1972-1974 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Sun Ra, 1973 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Sun Ra and Arkestra, Mexico, circa 1973-1974 (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - Sun Ra and Arkestra by Mike Harris, 1975 (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - Sun Ra and Arkestra, Chicago Old Style Jazz Festival, 1978 (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - Sun Ra, circa 1993 (Box 56, Folder 14)
    - Sun Ra, Schwarz, 1998 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Sun Ra and Arkestra, Chicago Old Style Jazz Festival, undated (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Sun Ra and Arkestra, undated (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Alton Abraham and friends, DuSable High School prom, circa 1940s (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Alton Abraham, undated (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - The Fabulous Chicago Links, circa 1960s (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - The Visitors, circa 1960s (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Lacy Gibson, circa 1960s (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP) Image Awards, 1972 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Dimpna B. Clarin and others, circa 1970s (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - Egypt, circa 1977-1978 (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - Egypt, circa 1977-1978 (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - Travel and outdoor scenes, 1975 (Box 57, Folder 13)
    - Travel and outdoor scenes, 1978 (Box 57, Folder 14)
    - Travel and outdoor scenes, circa 1978 (Box 57, Folder 15)
    - Travel and outdoor scenes, 1970s (Box 57, Folder 16)
    - Travel and outdoor scenes, 1988 (Box 57, Folder 17)
    - Travel and outdoor scenes, undated (Box 57, Folder 18)
    - Travel and outdoor scenes, undated (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Apollo mission, circa 1969 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified, 1962 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Notes, 1966 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Item 1: Sun Ra, New York, circa 1965 (Box 59)
    - Item 2: Sun Ra, Chicago, circa 1958 (Box 59)
    - Sun Ra and Arkestra in performance, by Harlan Robinson, undated (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Sun Ra and Arkestra, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Dimpna B. Clarin, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Wilson Junior College graduates, 1950 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Great Sphinx and pyramid, undated (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Landscape, undated (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Unidentified, circa 1960s-2000 (Box 61)
  - Subseries 2: Film and Video
    - "Sun Ra: Calling Planet Earth," two videocassettes, 1986 (Box 62)
    - Filmstrip fragment, undated (Box 62)
    - 8-millimeter films, 13 rolls, circa 1970s (Box 63)
    - Film box and canister, undated (Box 64)
    - "Sun Ra aux Halles," 16-millimeter film, 1970 (Box 65)
  - Subseries 3: Audio
    - Dimpna B. Clarin, "Sarung Banghi" / "Kagandahan Mo," Saturn 783, 45 rpm records, circa 1960s (Box 66)
    - Dimpna B. Clarin, "Hain Na Ang Panumpa?" / "Ave Maria," Saturn SR-4276/4277, 45 rpm records, circa 1960s (Box 66)
    - Cosmic Rays with Le Sun Ra and Arkestra, "Bye Bye" / "Somebody's In Love", Saturn 222, 45 rpm record, circa 1955 (Box 66)
    - Walt Dunn, "When You're in Love this Way," / "Perfidious Lover," Repeto 4233/4235, 45 rpm records, circa 1960s (Box 66)
    - Walt Dunn and the Metros, "Christina, Eugena, Marie," / "I'll Close My Heart," Repeto 4232/4235, 45 rpm records, circa 1960s (Box 66)
    - Lacy Gibson, "The Sky is Crying" / "She's My Baby," Saturn 436, 45 rpm records and inserts, circa 1960s (Box 66)
    - The Qualities, "It's Christmastime" / "Happy New Year to You," Saturn M08W4052/M08W4053, 45 rpm records, circa 1956 (Box 66)
    - Sun Ra and his Arkestra, "A Blue One," / "Orbitration in Blue," Saturn SRA-9991/9992, 45 rpm record, circa 1960s (Box 66)
    - Sun Ra and his Astro-Intergalactic Infinity Arkestra, "The Perfect Man," Saturn ES537B, 45 rpm record, circa 1960s (Box 66)
    - Sun Ra with NU Sounds, "Chicago USA"/ "Spaceship Lullaby," Stopsmiling 24, 45 rpm record, 2003 (Box 66)
    - Uptights Band, "Devil's on the Run" / "Mirrors Don't Ever Lie," Uptight 001, 45 rpm record, circa 1974 (Box 66)
    - Yochanan Yochanan, "Muck Muck (Matt Matt)" / "Hot Skillet Momma," Saturn 4236/4237, 45 rpm record, circa 1960 (Box 66)
    - Cosmic Rays with Le Sun Ra and Arkestra, "Bye Bye" / "Somebody's In Love", Saturn 222, 45 rpm record, circa 1955 (Box 67)
    - Little Mack, "Tell Her to Come on Home" / "I'm Making Believe," Saturn 144M, 45 rpm record, circa 1962 (Box 67)
    - The Qualities, "It's Christmastime" / "Happy New Year to You," Saturn M08W4052/M08W4053, 45 rpm record, circa 1956 (Box 67)
    - Sun-Ra and his Arkistra, "Soft Talk" / "Super Blonde," Saturn Z-1111, 45 rpm record, circa 1956 (Box 67)
    - Sun Ra and his Astro-Solar Infinity Arkestra, "Blues on Planet Mars" / "Saturn Moon," Saturn 911AR, 45 rpm record, circa 1968 (Box 68)
    - Yochanan Yochanan, "Muck Muck (Matt Matt)" / "Hot Skillet Momma," Saturn 4236/4237, 45 rpm record, circa 1960 (Box 68)
    - "Medicine for a Nightmare," test pressing, circa 1958 (Box 68)
    - "Blue Set," test pressing, circa 1959 (Box 68)
    - American Jazz and Blues History, Vol. 111 Sun Ra The Cosmos, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 69)
    - American Jazz and Blues History, Vol. 112 Sun Ra Cosmic Chaos, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 69)
    - Ann Arbor Blues and Jazz Festival 1972, Atlantic SD 2-502, 33 1/3 rpm record, 1972 (Box 69)
    - Sun Ra and his Myth Science Arkestra, Angels and Demons at Play, Saturn SR-9956-2-P, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 69)
    - Sun Ra, Astro Black, Impulse ABC Records AS-9255, 33 1/3 rpm record, 1973 (Box 69)
    - Sun Ra, Atlantis, Impulse ABC Records AS-9239, 33 1/3 rpm record, 1973 (Box 69)
    - Sun Ra and his Outer Space Arkestra, Celestial Love, Saturn C-1984-SG-9, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 69)
    - Sun Ra and his Myth Science Arkestra, Cosmos for Mental Therapy, Thoth KH-2772, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 69)
    - Sun Ra and his Astro Intergalactic Infinity Arkestra, Discipline 27-II, Saturn 538, 33 1/3 rpm record, 1973 (Box 69)
    - Sun Ra and his Arkestra, Dreams Come True, Saturn 485, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 69)
    - Sun Ra and his Myth-Science Arkestra, Fate in a Pleasant Mood, Saturn SR 9956-2, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 69)
    - Sun Ra, The Heliocentric Worlds of Sun Ra, ESP-Disk 1014, 33 1/3 rpm record, 1965 (Box 69)
    - Sun Ra and his Astro-Infinity Arkestra, Holiday for Soul Dance, Saturn SR-508, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 69)
    - Sun Ra and his Myth Science Arkestra, Interstellar Low Ways, Saturn SR-9956-2, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 69)
    - Sun Ra and his Solar Arkestra, Magic City, Saturn B-711, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 69)
    - Sun Ra and his Astro-Infinity Arkestra, My Brother the Wind, Saturn SR-1970, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 69)
    - Sun Ra and Astro-Intergalactic-Infinity Arkestra, Nature's God, Thoth 1272, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 69)
    - Sun Ra and his Astro-Solar Infinity Arkestra, The Night of the Purple Moon, Infinity IR 1972, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 69)
    - Sun Ra and his Astro-Solar Infinity Arkestra, The Night of the Purple Moon, Saturn IR 1972, 33 1/3 rpm record, 1974 (Box 69)
    - Sun Ra and his Myth-Science Arkestra, The Nubians of Plutonia, Saturn SR-9956-11, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 69)
    - Sun Ra and his Solar Arkestra, Other Planes of There, Saturn KH 98766, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 69)
    - Sun Ra and his Solar Arkestra, Planet Earth, Saturn 9956-11, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 69)
    - Sun Ra and his Solar Arkestra, Secrets of the Sun, Saturn FG-9954, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 69)
    - Sun Ra and his Astro-Infinity Arkestra, Strange Strange, Saturn KH-5472, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 69)
    - Sun Ra and his Myth Science Arkestra, Sun Song, Gravure Universelle GY 30002, 33 1/3 rpm record, 1971 (Box 69)
    - Sun Ra and his Arkestra, Super-Sonic Sounds, Impulse ABC Records AS-9271, 33 1/3 rpm record, 1974 (Box 69)
    - Sun Ra and his Blue Universe Arkestra, Universe in Blue, Saturn ESR 5000, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 69)
    - Sun Ra and His Myth-Science Arkestra, When Sun Comes Out, Saturn 2066, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 69)
    - Anal Magic and Reverend Dwight Frizzell, Beyond the Black Crack, Cavern Custom 6104-12, 33 1/3 rpm record, 1975 (Box 70)
    - Count Basie and his Orchestra, Pop Goes the Basie, Reprise R 6153, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 70)
    - Bhagwan Sree Adi Sankaracharya, Bhaja Govindam, Odeon Moce-2001, 33 1/3 rpm record, 1967 (Box 70)
    - Brown, Rev. T.E., Progressive Baptist Male Chorus, U-28182, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 70)
    - George Cates and his Orchestra, Coral 61618, undated (Box 70)
    - Dimpna B. Clarin / The Habagat Singers, Saturn 282, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 70)
    - Philip Cohran and the Artistic Heritage Ensemble, Zulu Records 0004, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 70)
    - Philip Cohran and the Artistic Heritage Ensemble, The Malcolm X Memorial, Zulu Records, 33 1/3 rpm record, 1970 (Box 70)
    - The Columbia World Library of Folk and Primitive Music, Southern Italy and the Islands, Columbia KL 5174, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 70)
    - Miles Davis, The Original Quintet (First Recording), Presitge PR 7254, 33 1/3 rpm record, 1962 (Box 70)
    - Ebenezer Missionary Baptist Church, Ebenezer's Singing Choirs, 744, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 70)
    - Gil Fuller and the Monterey Jazz Festival Orchestra, Night Flight, Pacific Jazz PJ-10101, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 70)
    - Erroll Garner, Erroll!, Mercury MG 36069, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 70)
    - Lucy Gibson, I Wish I Had a Wishing Ring, Saturn 528, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 70)
    - Normal Granz, Jazz at the Philharmonic, Disc Asch Recordings D455 V17, undated (Box 70)
    - Ernest Hare/Charles Hart and Elliott Shaw, "Gone, but not Forgotten" / "Swanee River Moon," Brunswick 2141, undated (Box 70)
    - Hyde Park Seventh Day Adventist Youth Choir, Oldney K. Rucker Director, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 70)
    - Curtis Jones, "Cool Playing Blues" / "Wrong Blues," Parrot 782, undated (Box 70)
    - Louis Jordan, "The Chicks I Pick Are Slender and Tender and Tall" / "What's the Use of Getting Sober (When You Gonna Get Drunk Again)," Decca 23629, undated (Box 70)
    - Mismillah Kahn, The Magic Shehnai of Mismillah Kahn, Odeon MOAE 122, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 70)
    - Gene Krupa and his Orchestra, "Let's Get Away From it All" / "Just a Little Bit South of North Carolina," Okeh 6130 (29976), undated (Box 70)
    - Lightnin' Hopkins, Talkin' Some Sense, Jewel Records 5001, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 70)
    - Jay McShann, "Hootie Boogie" / "Garfield Avenue Blues," Mercury, 8002, undated (Box 70)
    - Prince's Dance Orchestra / Yerkes Jazarimba Orchestra, "Dardanella" / Wild Flower Waltz," Columbia 2851, undated (Box 70)
    - The Savannah Syncopations, "Jackass Blues" / "Deep Henderson," Brunswick 3245, undated (Box 70)
    - The Shilo Chancel Choir and the St. Mary's Sr. Choir, The Holy City: Parts 1 and 2, Saturn 222, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 70)
    - The Shilo Chancel Choir and the St. Mary's Sr. Choir, The Holy City: Parts 3 and 4, Saturn 333, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 70)
    - The Shilo Chancel Choir and the St. Mary's Sr. Choir, The Holy City: Parts 3 and 4, Saturn 333, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 70)
    - Silver Echo, "Sinner Man" "Land of Fadeless Day," Manor 1011, undated (Box 70)
    - Victor Minstrel Company with Orchestra, "Tennessee Minstrels, No. 24" / Arthur Pryor's Band, "College Overture," Victor Record 35264, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 70)
    - Victor Minstrel Company with Orchestra, "Florida Minstrels, No. 25" / Ada Jones and Len Spencer, "A Race for a Wife," Victor Record 35267, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 70)
    - Fats Waller, '34/'35, RCA Victor LPV 516 (RPRM-7949), 33 1/3 rpm record, 1965 (Box 71)
    - Fats Waller, Fractious Fingering, RCA Victor LPV 537 (TPRM-5099), 33 1/3 rpm record, 1967 (Box 71)
    - Paul Whiteman and his Orchestra, "I Found a Four Leaf Clover" / "Two Little Ruby Rings," Victor 18950, undated (Box 71)
    - Paul Whiteman and his Orchestra, "I'm Bringing a Red-Red Rose" / "Making Whoopee!" Columbia 1683, undated (Box 71)
    - W.W. Williams, Back Diamond Rattler, Supreme Blues Records SR-1001, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 71)
    - Sonny Boy Williamson, Down and Out Blues, Chess 9508, 33 1/3 rpm record, undated (Box 71)
    - Test pressing, ASD-9276, undated (Box 71)
    - Test pressing, ASD-9276, undated (Box 71)
    - Test pressing, ASD-9288, undated (Box 71)
    - Test pressing, ASD-9288, undated (Box 71)
    - Test pressing, ASD-9289, 1974 (Box 71)
    - Test pressing, ASD-9289, 1974 (Box 71)
    - Test pressing, ASD-9290, 1974 (Box 71)
    - Test pressing, ASD-9290, 1974 (Box 71)
    - Test pressing, ASD-9293, 1974 (Box 71)
    - Test pressing, ASD-9294, 1974 (Box 71)
    - Test pressing, ASD-9295-A-2, ASD-9295-B-2, 1974 (Box 71)
    - Test pressing, ASD-9295-A-2, ASD 9295-B-2, 1974 (Box 71)
    - Test pressing, ASD-9295-A-2, ASD 9295-B-2, 1974 (Box 71)
    - Test pressing, ASD-9296, 1974 (Box 71)
    - Test pressing, ASD-9296, 1974 (Box 71)
    - Test pressing, ASD-9297-A-1, ASD-9297-B-2, 1974 (Box 71)
    - Jus Tu, Oriskhemqtua, cassette tape and correspondence, 1993 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Nat King Cole, The Unforgettable Nat King Cole, cassette tape, 1991 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Nakula, cassette tape, undated (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Kelan Phil Cochran, cassette tapes and correspondence, 1999 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Dr. Richard Denholm, "Mathematics: Structure and Skills," reel tape, 1968 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Unidentified reel tape, undated (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Radio broadcast, reel tape box fragment, 1971 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Berlin, Germany, reel tape box fragment, 1982 (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Reel tape box fragments, circa 1964 (Box 73)
    - Sister Angelica, McLin Opera Company, master reel tape, 1965 (Box 74)
    - Ethel N.L. Coleman, The Coleman Sociophonic Reading Design for All Ages, metal stampers and scripts, 1968 (Box 75)
- Series IX: Art and Artifacts
  Materials in this series fall into two broad categories: Art and artifacts related to Sun Ra, Saturn Records, and music in general; and personal items that belonged to Alton Abraham. In the first category are sample album jackets; proofs and layouts of album covers, catalogs and advertisements; drawings, sketches and paintings; photographs of artworks; musical instruments and equipment; metal stampers for vinyl records; printing blocks and office supplies. In the second category are decorative ornaments and personal items such as a wallet and a briefcase.
  Some items are matted or framed for display. These are organized together at the beginning of the series and arranged by size and format. The remaining items in the series are arranged by size. Most items are undated but generally span the late 1950s-1980s.
  This series includes a wealth of material documenting the process of designing and producing album covers for Sun Ra recordings. For some albums, there is original artwork, layout designs, album cover proofs, and sample album jackets. There are some alternate album cover artwork that was not used, and some for unreleased or possibly hypothetical recordings. Also included are several job files compiled by printing companies that produced packaging for reissued Sun Ra records in the 1970s and 1980s. These files consist of negatives, proofs and job specifications. Another unusual group of materials consists of thousands of record labels for Sun Ra albums. There is also artwork and layout material for albums by Lacy Gibson and Lena McLin. Names of performers and recordings are as given on the artwork or artifact. Artist names are given when identified on items; many artworks with no attributed artist are probably by Sun Ra.
  - Angels and Demons at Play, album jacket, framed (Box 76)
  - Discipline 27-II, album jacket, framed (Box 76)
  - Fate in a Pleasant Mood, album jacket, framed (Box 77)